<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>SustainableThreads - Blog</title>
  <updated>2021-05-14T11:09:29-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>SustainableThreads</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/artisan-update-from-india</id>
    <published>2021-05-14T11:09:29-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-14T11:09:29-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/artisan-update-from-india"/>
    <title>Artisan Update from India</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2><span>Seeking Support for Covid Response</span></h2>
<p><span>I will confess, for the first couple of weeks or more, our response to the second wave of Covid in India was emotional: the sense of anxiety and helplessness when you can’t be on the ground to assist was all-consuming. India has been hit hard by a second and more deadly wave of Covid that is ravaging the country. O</span><span>wing to severe shortage of medical supplies and hospital beds, s</span><span>tates around the country are reporting record daily cases and a mounting death toll.</span></p>
<p><span>We appreciate </span><span>that </span><span>some of you reached out to check in and seek ways to support artisan groups. In the last few days, we have been talking to group representatives. The Covid impact differs depending on the region as well as if artisans had workshop-based or home-based work. While artisans working from home are able to continue some work and earn hourly wages, workshops in most regions are closed down. But in every conversation, group representatives said it will be most helpful for them to continue receiving orders with a bit more flexibility on delivery timelines.</span></p>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/3_artisans_480x480.jpg?v=1620931779" alt="Artisans weaving-sewing" style="float: none;"> </div>
<p>While here at Sustainable Threads we plan to offer more production opportunities, we’re also considering helping and providing immediate assistance in the 2 projects mentioned below. If you, your friends or family wish to help, we invite you to consider supporting these efforts.</p>
<blockquote>
<strong>Dry Food Provisions*</strong>
<p>The food packets will include non-perishables - rice, flour, oil, lentils, sugar, turmeric and cardamom. Each packet costs $15 (helps a family of 4 with provisions for 2 weeks) and in the first leg they are planning to support 100 families. So, for one month’s supply the total support required is $3000. This project is organized by our physically challenged artisan groups.</p>
<div></div>
<strong>Artisan Support Fund*</strong>
<p>This fund, as an immediate response to the crisis, is for essential Covid medicines and oxygen supply for artisan communities. We are seeking a total of $3000 to be divided among a few groups. Local leaders have been requested to apply for medical help for their most needy artisans requiring treatment and they will be responsible for managing, reporting and presenting bills. In each case decisions will be taken by the organizational leaders.</p>
</blockquote>
<div>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.paypal.com/donate?business=U7N8F63QHTVJS&amp;item_name=Covid+response+-+support+for+artisans+%C2%A4cy_code=USD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">You may donate with PayPal</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span>You may Zelle the funds to 732.890.0515 </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Or please mail c<span>hecks to Poonam Abbi to be mailed to our company address shared below:</span><span><br></span><span>84 Riverbend Drive, </span>North Brunswick, NJ 08902</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote type="cite">
<div dir="ltr">
<div class="yiv4817792204ydpb2700bdyahoo-style-wrap">
<div dir="ltr">
<div style="text-align: center;"><span>We'd be grateful for any help extended. </span></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<div><em>*Most of the artisan groups we work with are not set up to receive ‘foreign’ funds. We hope to send them these funds via informal networks in India and so while we think we can get an acknowledgement letter of overall support received by the groups, we will not be able to provide tax deductible receipts.</em></div>
</blockquote>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/chickpeas-indian-style-recipe-chole-chana-masala</id>
    <published>2021-04-20T13:56:19-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-21T12:21:11-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/chickpeas-indian-style-recipe-chole-chana-masala"/>
    <title>From Ma&apos;s Kitchen: Chickpea Indian-style Recipe &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Punjabi Chole/Chana Masala</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>Photo features Poonam's mom, with her handwritten recipe for Chickpea (Chole Masala) Curry. Enjoy!</span></p>
<p><span>I learned to boil water at the age of 23 when I started my first job that was about 2 days' train journey from home-totally true! I quickly learned that I needed to cook as I had very limited means with which to provide myself 'real' food. What followed were old-fashioned, snail-mail letters and phone calls with my mom to get her recipes, techniques and insight. I also started really paying attention to other people as they cooked- specifically my colleagues and the people from the villages in which I worked. This journey of appreciating the art of cooking connected me to my mom in powerful and poignant ways (I guess we discover our connects with our mothers in often unsuspecting and common place things!).</span></p>
<p><span>My sister and I always reminisce about the vibrant tastes and smells from our Ma's kitchen! After all, food is a language of love. Food has a way of storytelling, and these stories need to be nourished and cultivated to nurture those who come after us.</span></p>
<span></span>
<div><span></span></div>
<div><span></span></div>
<div><span></span></div>
<p><span>In a way, Sustainable Threads' focus on the home came about quite organically but it is rooted in the art of storytelling through the home and most especially through what's on the table for all to share.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">
<span>From Ma's Kitchen:<br></span>Punjabi Chole Masala or Chana Masala (Serves 3)</h2>
<p>Punjabi Chole Masala or Chana Masala is a hugely popular curry dish from India. I have tweaked the recipe. I should mention here that my mother’s style of cooking is often based on ‘andaz’ (eyeballing) measurements. Please add or reduce the spices according to your taste.</p>
<blockquote>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px;">Ingredients</h3>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2 tsp Vegetable Oil</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">1 cup chopped Onion</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">3/4 tsp whole Cumin Seeds</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2-3 whole Bay Leaves</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">½ tsp Ginger paste</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">½ tsp Garlic paste</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">½ tsp Turmeric</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">½ tsp Red Chili powder, or as per taste</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Salt as per taste</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Pinch of Asafoetida (Hing) (optional)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">1 cup Chickpeas</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">4 cups water (including drained Chickpea water)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">3 tsp Chana Masala powder</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2 tsp Dry Mango (Amchur) powder and an additional 1/8 tsp as seasoning at the end</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2 tbsp chopped Cilantro for garnish</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">A few chopped Mint Leaves (optional)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Soak the Chickpeas overnight (7-8 hours) in enough water to cover them.<br><br>In a pressure cooker, heat Vegetable Oil. Once hot add Asafoetida if using, and Cumin Seeds. Once the Cumin Seeds start to splutter, add Bay Leaves. Next, add chopped Onion. Fry the Onion until light golden brown in color. Add Ginger and Garlic pastes and cook for another 3-4 minutes.</p>
<p><span>*You may cook this in an instant pot, too. Just put all the ingredients as suggested in the pressure cooker and then cook it on the bean/ chili setting in the instant pot. </span></p>
<p>Add the dry spices (other than Chana masala and Dry Mango powder) and Salt at this point and mix for 1-2 minutes.</p>
<p>Add the soaked and drained Chickpeas. Do not throw away the water once you have drained the Chickpeas. Now add water, including the drained water to make up the 4 cups of water.</p>
<p>Pressure cook on a high flame until the pressure cooker whistles once, then lower the flame to medium and let the Chickpeas cook for another 40 minutes. Remove the cooker from heat and allow it to cool down. Once the cooker has naturally released pressure, open it and check the Chickpeas. The Chickpeas should be soft enough to be able to crush them easily with your fingers or smash them with a spoon. If not, pressure cook until the cooker whistles 2 more times.</p>
<p>After the Chickpeas are soft, add Chana Masala and Dry Mango powder and cook without the lid for 3-4 minutes. </p>
<p>Garnish with the Cilantro and if using, the optional Mint Leaves. Finally, sprinkle 1/8<sup>th</sup> tsp of the Dry Mango powder evenly.</p>
<p>Enjoy Chole or Chana Masala with rice, flat bread, dinner rolls or any bread of your choice! </p>
<p>Add-on: You can serve it with chopped raw Onion and a few Lime wedges on the side.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/for-her-mothers-day-gift-ideas</id>
    <published>2021-04-19T20:43:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-19T20:43:37-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/for-her-mothers-day-gift-ideas"/>
    <title>For Her! Mother&apos;s Day Gift Ideas</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>From the bottom of our hearts, we at Sustainable Threads would like to wish a Happy Mother's Day to all the mothers, to the mothers who are both fathers and mothers, to the mothers who have loved and lost, to those yearning to be mothers and to all the people that you share your stories with.</p>
<div></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/JLxzrNdsT9SS8ChpVuMMTw_480x480.jpg?v=1618845125" alt="mothers and children"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div></div>
<p><span>And, here are a few handmade, fair trade gifts that may help your family tell its secrets for generations to come. We love being a part of your story.</span></p>
<div><span></span></div>
<div><a href="https://sustainablethreads.com/collections/for-her-mothers-day-gifts" target="_blank" title="Mother's Day Gift Ideas" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/251-72-KT.Fern_crop2_480x480.jpg?v=1618845214" alt="kitchen towel-fern" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></a></div>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><span>Kitchen Towels</span></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span>A great Kitchen Mate! Can one ever have enough of these?</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://sustainablethreads.com/collections/for-her-mothers-day-gifts" target="_blank" title="Mother's Day Gift Ideas" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/Paisley_2000x_crop-angle_5a8768c1-ada7-4243-a01d-21442e4ddf4a_480x480.jpg?v=1618871968" alt="paisley journal"></span></a></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><span>Journals</span></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span>For Mom who like journal-ling! Also great for writing recipes.</span> </p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://sustainablethreads.com/collections/for-her-mothers-day-gifts" target="_blank" title="Mother's Day Gift Ideas" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/DIFFERENTSTROKES4x5cards_envelopes1_2000x_nobkg_480x480.jpg?v=1618845304" alt="stationery"></span></a></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><span>Notecard Sets</span></h4>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span>For someone like me who loves to write (and get) hand written cards.</span></div>
<div><a href="https://sustainablethreads.com/collections/for-her-mothers-day-gifts" target="_blank" title="Mother's Day Gift Ideas" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/321-13-NP.Asparagus_crop_480x480.jpg?v=1618845320" alt="napkins-asparagus" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></a></div>
<div>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><span>Napkins</span></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span>To be enjoyed with each meal.</span></p>
</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/earth-day-talk-sustainability-if-imaginable</id>
    <published>2021-03-20T20:57:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-03-20T20:57:54-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/earth-day-talk-sustainability-if-imaginable"/>
    <title>Earth Day Talk: Sustainability is Imaginable!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Thursday, April 22 is Earth Day</h2>
<p><span>It’s an event that has become important more than ever before. We recognize our buying habits will continue to dictate the debate of our planet’s health and well-being. Where our products come from, who is behind them, and its impact on local and global environment plays an important role in this deliberation. Fair Trade principles emphasize the importance of environmental and human safety, welfare and happiness.</span></p>
<p><span>We are proud to do our little bit, by adhering to fair trade practices and to feature some of our most environmentally-friendly, reusable cloth napkins for Earth Day month!</span></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/301-300-NK_INDIGO_SEA_sq_240x240.jpg?v=1616204295" alt="Organic Cotton Napkins"></div>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span>Organic Cotton Napkins</span></h3>
<p><span>We partnered with a local community to use indigenous organic cotton, to create napkins. This cotton is grown without synthetic pesticides, herbicides or insecticides, and is never genetically engineered. Natural, plant-dyes are used in creating this collection.</span></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/311-05-LN_BlueCorn_sq_240x240.jpg?v=1616204341" alt="Flax Linen Napkins" style="float: none;"></div>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Flax Linen Napkins</h3>
<div style="text-align: left;">Linen is one of the most biodegradable and stylish fabrics in the textile home goods sector. It is strong, naturally moth resistant, and made from flax plant fibers. Flax grows naturally and requires no additional irrigation other than rainwater, making it one of the most eco-friendly fabrics. Our flax linen napkins are also woven by hand and made in small batches with incredibly low impacts to the environment, without modern machinery. The small amount of water that is used, is treated before its release back into the environment.</div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/301-219-BV_BLUE_VALLEY_sq_240x240.jpg?v=1616204317" alt="Kora Unbleached Cotton" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<h3>Kora Unbleached Cotton Napkins </h3>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<p>Kora in Hindi means raw and unprocessed. This cotton uses no harsh chemical dyes and therefore requires a negligible amount of energy, resulting in a less harmful method of textile production. Dyed with low impact, azo-free dyes that are stamped by hand and made in assembly-free, small artisan workshops.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span>All projects are Earth-friendly, which entails they help disadvantaged handicraft artisan communities, aim to improve the socio-economic status of the community, practice mindfulness toward the environmen</span><span>t</span><span> </span><span>and above all, keep dying arts alive!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/Artisan-round_240x240.jpg?v=1616205231" alt="Artisan holding cotton" width="240x240" height="240x240" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/celebrate-your-extra-special-family-moments-with-extra-special-fair-trade-creations</id>
    <published>2021-02-26T22:29:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-26T22:29:49-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/celebrate-your-extra-special-family-moments-with-extra-special-fair-trade-creations"/>
    <title>Celebrate your extra-special family moments with extra-special fair trade creations!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3><span>Set your Easter table with alluring pastel shades and soft silk</span></h3>
<p><span>A table set for the occasion inspires the most warm and joyful connections and conversations. Beautify your table this Easter holiday with soft, silk runners in serene Spring colors!</span></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://sustainablethreads.com/collections/the-easter-table"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/Sustainable_Threads_Easter0139_480x480.jpg?v=1614302140" alt="" style="float: none;"></a></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<p><span>Our handcrafted lovelinesses are made in small batches - every phase of its production ensures minimal impact to the environment. Disadvantaged, physically challenged artisans are able to earn a sustainable, fair living from spinning and weaving work.</span></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/Artisan-Spinning-Bobbin-winding-sm_480x480.jpg?v=1614301991" alt="artisan spinning" style="float: none;" width="480x480" height="480x480"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/print-celebrations</id>
    <published>2021-01-19T20:35:29-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T20:35:29-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/print-celebrations"/>
    <title>Print Celebrations</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span>Our springtime prints make quite the impression! </span></h3>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span>Choose from tablecloths, placemats and napkins. Our block prints done by hand, one stamp at a time, are unique because of the fabric and designs. The </span><span>100% kora cotton</span><span> fabric</span><span> (unprocessed and unbleached), means the original color of the cotton crop is retained, and is complemented by our exclusive block print designs.</span></p>
<div><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/blocks-for-print_rev_480x480.jpg?v=1610998487" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span></span></h3>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span>Making an impression</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span>Artisans first carve designs on wooden blocks. In order to make a single impression they ensure the block is lined up correctly, firmly placing it on the fabric and pressing down with force to evenly distribute dye over the fabric. The pattern is then repeated hundreds of times to finish one product.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/Printing-in-SMK_crop_480x480.jpg?v=1610998512" alt=""></span></h3>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span>Unique imperfections</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span>Imperfections make hand block printing especially special, unlike machine-made uniform prints.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/301-218-BR_BLUE_ROBBIN_SKU_1_480x480.jpg?v=1610998528" alt=""></span></h3>
<span style="color: #217b3e;"><a href="https://sustainablethreads.com/collections/hello-summer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #217b3e;">View our block print collection!</a></span>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/grateful-for-our-community</id>
    <published>2020-12-22T19:12:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T19:12:03-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/grateful-for-our-community"/>
    <title>Grateful for Our Community</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p align="center"><span>In this extraordinary year, your partnership has given us hope and courage. To quote Martin Luther King:</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p align="center"><strong><span style="color: #298921;"><em>"We must accept finite disappointment, but never lose infinite hope."</em></span></strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p align="center"><span>We are signing off this year with that thought.</span></p>
<p align="center"><span>May the magical time of Christmas and New Year fill your life with goodness and blessings.</span></p>
<p align="center"><span>Merry Christmas and our sincerest wishes for 2021 to you and yours.</span></p>
<p align="center"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/border_240x240.gif?v=1607622409" alt="Christmas Graphic"></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/a-package-deal</id>
    <published>2020-12-11T09:46:57-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T09:46:57-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/a-package-deal"/>
    <title>Gifting Stories!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h4>
<span>Sustainable Threads’ products are conversation pieces</span><span> </span><span>for more than a few reasons:</span>
</h4>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Artisans</strong> – indigenous crafts persons who practice old and dying art forms &amp; physically challenged artisans that are trained in income-generating crafts</li>
<li>
<strong>Techniques</strong> – block printing, spinning and weaving by hand</li>
<li>
<strong>Raw materials</strong> – cruelty-free silk &amp; kora or unprocessed cotton</li>
<li>
<strong>Tools</strong> – hand-carved printing blocks &amp; bamboo looms</li>
<li>
<strong>Environmentally-friendly</strong> – fair trade, 100% handcrafted and low-impact dyes</li>
<li>
<strong>Social and physical context of the regions</strong> where the products are made, influencing and impacting the merchandise and its production.</li>
</ol>
<div></div>
<p><span>We make every attempt to bring these elements to our retail partners through our packaging. Our effort is to make our hang tags, hangers and bands educate as well as provide an experience to the purchaser! It is our endeavor that a shopper enjoys not just the product, but also the stories behind them.</span></p>
<h6 style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://441cm8f51i8q7kih-20102557.shopifypreview.com/collections/kitchen-dining" target="_blank" title="Sustainable Threads Kitchen &amp; Dining" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/package-details-reduced_480x480.jpg?v=1607622233" alt=""></a></h6>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Packaging that displays our brand’s ideas of simplicity, attractive designing and eco-friendliness.<br></em><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/border_480x480.gif?v=1607622409" alt="Christmas graphic"></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/happy-diwali</id>
    <published>2020-11-12T09:44:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-12T09:44:14-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/happy-diwali"/>
    <title>Happy Diwali!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div>
<span>We celebrate Diwali this upcoming weekend. It’s a five day Hindu festival, meaning “cluster of lights”.</span> <span>Diwali traditionally includes cleaning your homes and businesses on or before the first day allowing for a fresh start! People decorate homes and their doorways on the second day. They celebrate Dhanteras, to invite good luck, wealth and prosperity in their lives. </span><span>Chhoti Diwali and Diwali evenings starts after performing pooja (prayers). Pople light diyas/candles and burst crackers. Food is very central (my most favorite part!) people make and offer delicious sweets or delectable savories. The last day of Diwali is Bahi Dooj that celebrates the brother-sister relationship!</span>
<div class="yiv1519324387ydp88ebd45bMsoNormal"><span>There are many countries and cultures that celebrate festivals of lights – Tihar in Nepal, Hannukah, the Jewish celebration, Loi Krathong, a Buddhist holiday from Thailand, Kwanzaa an African American celebration of African culture and roots, Christmas is a Christian holiday that celebrates the birth of the baby Jesus.<br clear="none"></span></div>
<div class="yiv1519324387ydp88ebd45bMsoNormal"><span> </span></div>
<div class="yiv1519324387ydp88ebd45bMsoNormal"><span>These winter lights represent symbolic victory of light over darkness, knowledge over ignorance, and good over evil; express people’s hopes for peace, understanding and possibilities. Happy Diwali!</span></div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/cheering-for-fair-trade-month-and-fresh-stocks-have-arrived</id>
    <published>2020-10-18T12:35:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-10-18T12:35:03-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/cheering-for-fair-trade-month-and-fresh-stocks-have-arrived"/>
    <title>Cheering for Fair Trade month and fresh stocks have arrived!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span>October is Fair Trade month!</span></h3>
<p><span>Fair Trade invites us to think about our purchases; where they come from and who the producers are. Conscious purchasing habits of our customers have helped us invest in our artisan communities. Thank you for being a part of our work, especially given the extraordinary challenges this year brought! Fair Trade Federation aptly illustrates (in graphic below) Fair Trade principles that we collectively support!</span></p>
<p><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/FTF-Principles_480x480.png?v=1602984043" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p><span>We are also happy to announce the first of the few shipments that many of you have been waiting for, has arrived – in time for Thanksgiving! We've updated item availability on our website. Please place your orders and we hope to start shipping soon.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/Linen-Set-Lifestyle-10-20-hp_480x480.jpg?v=1602978678" alt=""></span></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Flax linen runners and napkins, perfect for your Thanksgiving table.</em></p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Happy Fair Trade Month!</h3>
<p> </p>
</blockquote>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/sustainable-threads-introduces-a-reversible-organic-cotton-face-mask-collection</id>
    <published>2020-09-30T12:44:55-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-30T12:44:55-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/sustainable-threads-introduces-a-reversible-organic-cotton-face-mask-collection"/>
    <title>Sustainable Threads Introduces A Reversible, Organic Cotton Face Mask Collection</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span>We are pleased to work with our artisan partners to bring you reversible face mask collections. </span>Breathe free and easy with our lightweight and reusable face masks. No strong or harmful chemicals are used in any of our fabric. You stay snug in cooler temps and comfy in hot or balmy weather!</p>
<div style="text-align: right;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/Organic-Cotton-Face-Masks_480x480.jpg?v=1601250850" style="margin-bottom: 2px; float: right;" width="480x480" height="480x480"></div>
<div align="center" style="text-align: left;"><strong>Organic Cotton Face Masks</strong></div>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: left;">
<div>100% Organic cotton</div>
</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">
<div>Handwoven</div>
</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">
<div>Reversible </div>
</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">
<div>All-natural plant-based dyes</div>
</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">
<div style="text-align: left;">Candle Blow Test grade</div>
</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>We also have other attractive collections made from Hand Block printed and Handwoven cotton, dyed with low-impact dyes.</p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/HeraBlockPrintFacemask_480x480.jpg?v=1601250048" alt="block print face masks" style="margin-top: 8px; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 8px; float: left;" width="480x480" height="480x480"></div>
<span>Handcrafted from 100% cotton, the collections are pleated to help expand (or not) depending on each individual’s comfort and are reversible with coordinating designs on each side - with no wrong sides. Universal size. Sold in sets of two.</span>
<div style="text-align: right;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/HandwovenCottonFacemask_480x480.jpg?v=1601250097" alt="cotton face mask" style="margin-top: 8px; float: right;"></div>
<div></div>
<div align="center"><span>Available in our online store: </span></div>
<div align="center"><a href="https://sustainablethreads.com/collections/face-masks" target="_blank" title="Reversible Orgainic Cotton Face Masks" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://sustainablethreads.com/collections/face-masks</a></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/a-look-behind-the-scenes-at-sustainable-threads</id>
    <published>2020-08-24T09:11:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-24T09:32:12-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/a-look-behind-the-scenes-at-sustainable-threads"/>
    <title>A look behind the scenes at Sustainable Threads</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Meet the folks who help us create and communicate our brand values.</strong></h3>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Please meet Christine Armstrong</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/Chris37_2_4617712c-62e2-4599-93a6-4cac2568d29b_large.jpg?v=1598234375" style="float: none;"></p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">
<span><em>“</em></span><em>Stop wondering how it feels to get the photos your brand deserves.”<br></em>― Christine Armstrong</h3>
<div></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/Linen_Group_large.jpg?v=1592445620" alt=""></div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span>Chris uses her lens (literally!) to present our exclusive products to you. We’ve worked with her for over 4 years now. I just noticed that our first set of products were shipped to her in January 2016 for a photo shoot. But before that Chris worked with us via emails and many phone calls to help us collectively arrive at what we wanted to communicate. She says of her philosophy:</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span><em>“Ask questions first! Good communication is the key.”</em></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span>Well, I suspect that’s a good philosophy for every relationship.</span></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/Clyde-at-work_web_large.jpg?v=1598236255" alt=""></span></div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span>Chris works her magic from a renovated barn loft at their farm in Baltimore. She has 17 rescue kittens that she is currently caring for. Don’t miss the one that participated in the photo shoot!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/BlockPrintNapkins_Lifestyle_web_large.jpg?v=1592445501" alt=""></span></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span>In response to the many sad stories Chris read about migrants in India during lock down, she offered for us to use part of a generous payment we owed her for the artisan groups we worked with. We are touched by her gesture and this speaks to the bonds of trust and friendship she offers people and products she works with.</span></div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Thanks much, Chris. </em></p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span>More of our favorite shots of our fair trade products.</span></h3>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/WovenTeas_large.jpg?v=1592445586" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/SustainableThreads13444_Napkin_Group_large.jpg?v=1592445655" style="float: none;"></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/BlockPrint-Set_Lifestyle_web_large.jpg?v=1592445431" alt=""></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><span>Learn more about Christine Armstrong at </span></h4>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.armstrongstudios.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-link-type="web">www.armstrongstudios.com</a></h4>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/embrace</id>
    <published>2020-06-20T22:51:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-21T21:02:01-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/embrace"/>
    <title>Emb(race)</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h3><span>We want to acknowledge what’s staring us in the face.</span></h3>
<div>
<span>Sustainable Threads has always been about being socially conscious and recognizing that we are all interconnected. Our business was founded on the concepts of counting on community. The acknowledgment of, and work on racial (in)justice is an extension of that idea. As individuals, our capacity to carry out that work differs – regardless, it is important that we do the work. Whether we are marching on the streets, voicing our opinions on social media, donating towards the cause, </span><span>we are speaking about the issues within our own homes</span><span>, or simply reading books and articles to check our own bias(es), rest assured that collectively, engaging in this work and in the process of (un)learning, we have and will continue to create a positive local and global impact.</span>
</div>
<div><span></span></div>
<div><span>We share this image that spoke to us.</span></div>
<div><a href="http://www.miabirdsong.com/how-we-show-up" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/artwork_large.jpg?v=1592617617" alt=""></span></a></div>
<div><span></span></div>
<div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><span>Protests have their legitimate space and here are some ideas that I found particularly helpful for our ongoing search for social justice:</span></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2020/06/07/870251488/beyond-protests-5-more-ways-to-channel-anger-into-action-to-fight-racism" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" data-link-type="undefined" title="Beyond Protests: 5 More Ways To Channel Anger Into Action To Fight Racism" style="color: #38761d;">Beyond Protests: 5 More Ways To Channel Anger Into Action To Fight Racism</a></span></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><span></span></div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/wishes-for-mothers-day-and-fair-trade-day</id>
    <published>2020-05-09T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-30T12:44:30-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/wishes-for-mothers-day-and-fair-trade-day"/>
    <title>Wishes for Mother&apos;s Day and Fair Trade Day</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>May 9<sup>th</sup> is World Fair Trade Day,</strong><span> a day to celebrate and raise awareness of Fair Trade practices. Your partnership increases the visibility of this movement. A sincere thanks for it.</span></p>
<p><span>Using this time to give you an update about the artisans we collectively support. We’ve been in frequent contact with as many artisan representatives as possible. India is under lockdown, although the numbers of confirmed Covid-19 cases reported are still quite low as compared to many other countries around the world. The key strategy seems to be to prevent spread of the disease. Families are confined in small spaces and their incomes have been gravely affected.</span></p>
<p><span>A couple of home-based groups continued to work until the raw materials ran out, while a couple of groups are able to create masks for sale as they are based closer to the cities. But of course, the casual migrant workers are affected most adversely, with no ability to afford to live in cities without income and unable to return to their villages because of the surprise lockdown that began in the last week of March (citizens did not receive prior notice of the nationwide mass quarantine.) Some state governments have been delivering much-needed emergency food relief to low-income families. There is no one story, no simple answers but a patchwork of responses, some hopeful, some not. </span></p>
<p><span>At Sustainable Threads, we are working to pay the groups as able, for the orders we have placed for, whenever they are ready. We hope this helps them endure at least some uncertainties.</span></p>
<p><span>A friend shared the following with us and I think it’s a great reminder for why we are all doing this…</span></p>
<blockquote>
<div style="text-align: center;"><em><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2010/2557/files/6f008711-e970-4c9a-befa-7484c69b7b12_480x480.jpg?v=1601353820" width="480x480" height="480x480" style="float: none;"></em></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em></em></div>
</blockquote>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em>“In a world where news of inhumanity bombards our sensibilities, where grasping for things goes so far beyond our needs, where time is squandered in busyness, it is a pleasure and a privilege to pause for a look at handiwork, to see beauty amidst utility, and to know that craft traditions begun so long ago serve us today.”</em></div>
<div align="right"><em>― John Wilson </em></div>
<div align="right">
<div style="text-align: center;"><span>And on that beautiful note,</span></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><strong>Happy Mother’s Day! And Happy Fair Trade Day!</strong></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span>In friendship,</span></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span>Poonam &amp; Harish</span></div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/a-time-to-reflect</id>
    <published>2020-03-27T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-30T12:43:27-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://sustainablethreads.com/blogs/news/a-time-to-reflect"/>
    <title>A Time To Reflect</title>
    <author>
      <name>Poonam Abbi</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"><span>We are staying hopeful at Sustainable Threads in this uncertain time, although the day-to-day has been a challenge. However, we are carving out work that may be useful down the road… We hope very much that you, your families and colleagues are staying safe and keeping healthy.</span></p>
<div align="center" style="text-align: left;"></div>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"><span>We recently came across this poem, "And the people stayed home" that resonated with us deeply and we think you will enjoy reading it, and feel empowered to take small actions that may provide hope. The picture here is from a walk around our neighborhood park, capturing first signs of spring!</span></p>
<p align="center" style="text-align: left;"><span>Best wishes,<br></span>Poonam and Harish</p>
<div align="center" style="text-align: left;"><span></span></div>
<blockquote>
<div align="center" style="text-align: left;">
<h3><span>"And the People Stayed Home"</span></h3>
<div><span>And people stayed home</span></div>
<div><span>and read books and listened</span></div>
<div><span>and rested and exercised</span></div>
<div><span>and made art and played</span></div>
<div><span>and learned new ways of being</span></div>
<div><span>and stopped</span></div>
<div><span>and listened deeper</span></div>
<div><span>someone meditated</span></div>
<div><span>someone prayed</span></div>
<div><span>someone danced</span></div>
<div><span>someone met their shadow</span></div>
<div><span>and people began to think differently</span></div>
<div><span>and people healed</span></div>
<div><span>and in the absence of people who lived in ignorant ways,</span></div>
<div><span>dangerous, meaningless and heartless,</span></div>
<div><span>even the earth began to heal</span></div>
<div><span>and when the danger ended</span></div>
<div><span>and people found each other</span></div>
<div><span>grieved for the dead people</span></div>
<div><span>and they made new choices</span></div>
<div><span>and dreamed of new visions</span></div>
<div><span>and created new ways of life</span></div>
<div><span>and healed the earth completely</span></div>
<div><span>just as they were healed themselves.</span></div>
<div align="right"></div>
<div align="right" style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: left;"><span>Kitty O’Meara</span></div>
</div>
</blockquote>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
